Guide to the Local Newspapers on Microfilm Collection BCMS.0028
Brooklyn Collection
- Brooklyn Tablet (The Tablet), 1908-1985; 96 Reels (Bin 35)
  The Brooklyn Tablet provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of the Catholic community. National and international news concerning Catholics is also covered. Some obituaries for prominent Catholics appear. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in the paper. Numerous photos of local clergy appear, as do reprints of sermons given by local priests. Directories of Catholic clubs and societies regularly appear. Graduation announcements and honor rolls from local Catholic schools also regularly appear. Sports news is largely relegated to coverage of CYO events. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
  Issues prior to 1964 are available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. That content is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
- Brooklyn Tenant, 1977; Partial reel (same reel as North Brooklyn News). (Bin 30)
  Largely focusing on the areas of Flatbush, Midwood, Kings Highway, Gravesend, and Sheepshead Bay, the Brooklyn Tenant provides local news coverage of politics, education, and housing concerns. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. The paper is largely devoted to news related to rental properties, renter's rights, and housing issues. News of the Flatbush Tenants Council is regularly covered. Consistent coverage is also given to the Koch/Cuomo mayoral primary. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Times, 1964-1979; 17 Reels (Bin 12)
  Largely focusing on South Brooklyn, the Brooklyn Times provides news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Lists of military deployments regularly appear in the paper. Consistent coverage is also given to a paper-sponsored "Beautiful Baby Contest." Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Times Union, 1932-1937; 99 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm shelves)
  The Brooklyn Times Union provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Some national and international news coverage is also provided. Death notices appear regularly in the paper. A women's fashion section regularly appears, as does an aviation section. Sunday editions contain some wedding and engagement announcements. Birth announcements do not appear. Advertisements and illustrations appear throughout. In March of 1932 the Brooklyn Daily Times merged with The Standard Union and both titles were on the masthead until June, when the paper was renamed the Brooklyn Times Union.
- Brooklyn Today, 1971-1973; 1 Reels (Bin 12)
  Brooklyn Today provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear. Brief histories of different Brooklyn neighborhoods are featured in each issue. A chess column and neighborhood by neighborhood reports also appear regularly. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Weekly Eagle, 1842-1845; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Content of the Brooklyn Weekly Eagle mainly consists of national and international news briefs. The news coverage is not particularly local in scope, though consistent coverage of state politics appears. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in the paper. Death notices occasionally appear, but there is no section devoted to them. Illustrations and photographs do not appear in the paper.
- Canarsie Courier, 1956-1999; 97 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Canarsie, the Canarsie Courier provides news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Wedding announcements and engagement announcements occasionally appear. Birth announcements do not appear. Obituaries regularly appear in the paper. Church and religious news, particularly of the Jewish community, appears regularly. A column called "What Our Servicemen Are Doing," providing a roundup of Canarsie community members serving in the military, appears regularly during the Vietnam War era. Later issues include a "Medical Update" section featuring health news and a "Congratulations Graduates" section covering school graduations. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Canarsie Digest, 1967-1999; 147 Reels (Bin 14, Bin 15, Bin 16)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Canarsie, the Canarsie Digest provides news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A fashion column regularly appears as does a "Scouting News" column, covering the activities of both boy scouts and girl scouts. Later issues include numerous dining reviews as well as full menus from local restaurants. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Caravan, 1953-1961; 4 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  A paper of local, national, and international scope devoted to the Arab-American community, The Caravan provides news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Within the Arab-American community, particular attention is paid to the Syrian and Lebanese populations. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries all appear regularly. A section called "Servicemen" news also regularly appears. Poetry, in Arabic and translated into English, regularly appears. A section called "Oriental Dishes" is also regularly published and features recipes of Middle Eastern cuisine. A column about dating and courtship in the Arab-American community entitled "Of Girls and Boys" also regularly appears. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier, 1991-1993; 4 Reels (Bin 17)
  Focusing on the neighborhoods of Carroll Gardens and Cobble Hill. (See also: Brooklyn Paper—Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill & The Newspaper.)
- Coney Island Times, 1955-1956, 1962, 1969, 1974-1979; 7 Reels (Bin 18)
  Focusing on the neighborhoods of Coney Island, Bensonhurst, Gravesend, Boro Park, Brighton Beach, Manhattan Beach, and Sheepshead Bay, the Coney Island Times provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Death notices for prominent Brooklynites are occasionally published. Profiles of local residents are printed in a regularly appearing column called "About Important People." News concerning the Red Cross is also regularly provided, as is Boy Scout news. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Daily Long Island Democrat, 1895, February 1911-September 1912.; 23 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the area of Jamaica, Queens the Daily Long Island Democrat provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Coverage of the greater New York City area is also provided. Birth announcements do not appear, however lists of marriage licenses do. Death notices appear for prominent New Yorkers appear. "Ball and Bat Notes," a column devoted to baseball at the national level, is regularly printed and includes photos of many players. Advertisements, illustrations, and some photographs appear throughout.
- Downtown News, 1988-1999; 7 Reels (Bin 17)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Downtown Brooklyn, Red Hook, Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill, Park Slope, and Brooklyn Heights, Downtown News provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A column called "Brownstone Brooklyn People," highlighting the personal and professional accomplishments of the area's residents, regularly appears. Profiles of local businesses also appear regularly in a section entitled "Business Brooklyn." Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- East New Yorker, 1975-1981; 1 Reels (Bin 17)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of East New York, the East New Yorker provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A column called "Woman/Man of the Month," profiling East New Yorkers regularly appears, as does a column entitled "Spotlight on East New York" which highlights the work of East New Yorkers involved in the arts community. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Flatbush Life, 1959-1999; 160 Reels (Bin 17, Bin 25, Bin 26, Bin 27)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Flatbush, Flatbush Life provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in early issues of the paper but occasional appear in later issues. A section devoted to obituaries regularly appears in early issues but not in later issues. Early issues of the paper also contain a section called "Bowling Life" covering league activity at neighborhood alleys. Numerous advertisements for bowling lanes and equipment providers also appear. A section called "Glenwood Observer," covering the news of that neighborhood, also regularly appears in early issues of the paper. A column entitled "Who's Who in East Flatbush" provides profiles and photographs of local residents. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Flatbush Times, November 1952 and 1954; very few issues 1953, 1955, 1957, 1959; 2 Reels (Bin 18)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Flatbush and East Flatbush, the Flatbush Times provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Wedding announcements and engagements announcements occasionally appear as part of the column "In the Social Spotlight." A column called "News of Flatbush GIs" regularly appears as does a section called "VFW Notes." Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Flatbush Weekly & Kings County Record, 1904-1906; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Content of the Flatbush Weekly and Kings County Record mainly consists of local news briefs providing coverage of education, religion, clubs and organizations, business, politics, and community events. In addition to the Flatbush neighborhood, sections devoted to news coverage in Windsor Terrace and Vanderveer Park also appear. A column called "Obituary Notes" regularly appears, but birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear. Advertisements and photos appear throughout.
- Garden Spot News, 1971-1980; 2 Reels (Bin 37)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Greenpoint and Williamsburg, the Garden Spot News provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper, however wedding and engagements announcements occasionally appear. A section devoted to obituaries regularly appears. A column called "Ring Notes," covering Brooklyn boxing news, regularly appears. The paper also consistently features large photo spreads of events in the area—from The Feast of Our Lady at Mt. Carmel to shots of people in McCarren Park. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Greater Brooklyn, April 5 - November 22, 1895.; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Published by the League of Loyal Citizens, Greater Brooklyn was a short-lived anti-consolidationist newspaper. The paper covered such topics revolving around the issue of consolidation as taxation, education, and the benefits of small local government. The president of the League of Loyal Citizens was William C. Redfield who would later serve as Secretary of Commerce under President Woodrow Wilson.
- Greenline, 1978-1980; 1 Reels (Bin 19)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Williamsburg and Greenpoint, Greenline provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, and sports. Births, weddings, communions, and anniversaries regularly appear in a column called "Transitions." Obituaries do not appear in the paper. Published by the St. Nicholas Neighborhood Preservation and Housing Rehabilitation Corporation, the paper consistently covers issues concerning apartment renovation, neighborhood architecture, and neighborhood preservation. Other regularly appearing columns include: "Greenline Gourmet Group" which consists of restaurant reviews, and "Senior Power," a column devoted to news of the area's elderly population. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Greenpoint Gazette [and Advertiser], 1980-1998; 21 Reels (Bin 19)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Greenpoint, the Greenpoint Gazette [and Advertiser] provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear, however wedding and engagement announcements occasionally appear. A section devoted to obituaries appears regularly. Regular coverage in the paper is given to the Friends of McGolrick Park organization as well as the Civilian Observation Patrol. A column called "Firenews," reporting on area fires and written by a fireman, also appears regularly. The Mt. Carmel and Our Lady of the Snow feasts are also given regular coverage. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout. The title of the publication starts and ends as Greenpoint Gazette and Advertiser, but for a period in the middle of its run, from January 1981 until December 1986, it is just Greenpoint Gazette.
- Greenpoint Home News, 1956-1958; 2 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  The Greenpoint Home News provides city-wide news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A "Men in Service" column, detailing deployments, graduations, and promotions, regularly appears. News relating to the Jewish community is also regularly covered. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Greenpoint Weekly Star, 1956-1968; 10 Reels (Bin 18, Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Greenpoint and Williamsburg, the Greenpoint Weekly Star Gazette provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper. Wedding, engagement, and anniversary announcements, sometimes accompanied by photographs, appear in a section called "Society News." Death notices and obituaries regularly appear. A column called "Friends and Neighbors," profiling neighborhood residents, also regularly appears, as does the column "If You're Goin' Fishin'," which provides local fishing news. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Home Talk, 1901-1929; 11 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the area of South Brooklyn, Home Talk provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper. Wedding and engagement announcements appear regularly, as do death notices. A section called "Timely Topics for the Gentle Sex," a page devoted to fashion and women's issues, regularly appears. Articles about minstrel shows in the area are also regularly printed. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Home Talk Item, 1906-1931; 3 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the area of South Brooklyn, Home Talk Item provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries are all regularly printed. Regularly appearing columns include: "Be Prepared," a column devoted to Boy Scout news; a "Theatres" column as well as a "Radio" column; "Motor News from Road and Showroom," devoted to automobile news; and "Boost Bay Ridge," a business review page. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Home Talk Star, 1928-1931; 4 Reels (Bin 22)
- Home Talk Star & Item, 1932-1938; 6 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Bay Ridge, the Home Talk Star and Item provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Item, 1906-1927; 4 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the area of South Brooklyn, The Item provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper. Wedding and engagement announcements appear regularly, as do death notices. Advertisements, photographs, and illustrations appear throughout.
- Kings County Chronicle, 1956-1969; 12 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers, Bin 18)
  Issues to 1964 are available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. That content is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of East New York and Brownsville, the Kings County Chronicle provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Veteran news appears regularly, including the columns: "American Legionnaire" and "V.F.W. News." Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Kings County Inspector, 1892-1893; 1 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Bensonhurst, New Utrecht, Bay Ridge, Fort Hamilton, and Bath Beach, the Kings County Inspector provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper. Wedding announcements and obituaries occasionally appear. Lists of real estate transfers as well as Brooklyn-wide amusements are regularly printed. Opinion pieces appear regularly as does a column called "The Inspector's Notebook" which provides brief announcements of neighborhood residents' activities. Local baseball coverage appears frequently and includes box scores for Bensonhurst and Brighton games as well as scorecards for upcoming games with the names of players listed. Issues also contain political cartoons relating to issues of local political and civic life. Advertisements and illustrations appear throughout.
- Kings County Rural & Brooklyn (Brighton) Gazette, 1880-1885; 3 Reels (Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Flatbush, Flatlands, Gravesend, and New Utrecht, the Kings County Rural and Brooklyn Gazette provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, and religion. Birth announcements do not appear in the paper. In a section called "Long Island Items," coverage of Long Island weddings and deaths is provided. Other regularly appearing columns include: "Railroad Notes" and "Farm and Garden." A Flatbush business directory is also regularly printed. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Kings County Rural Gazette, 1872-1879; 3 Reels
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Flatbush, Bay Ridge, New Utrecht, Gravesend, Canarsie, and Sheepshead Bay, the Kings County Rural Gazette, provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, clubs and organizations, community events, and religion. Early issues of the paper do not contain birth announcements, wedding announcements, or obituaries; however, these items appear in later issues. The paper's content largely consists of miscellany, religious notes, fashion items, and brief articles on events in area neighborhoods. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Kings Courier, 1955-1998; 131 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers, Bin 18, Bin 23, Bin 24, Bin 37)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of South Flatbush, The Kings Courier provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. The Kings Courier combines the former Kingsway Courier, Midwood Courier, and Avenue U News. Wedding, engagement, and Bar Mitzvah announcements all appear in a column called "Society Hi-Lites." Obituaries do not appear in the paper. Early issues of the paper provide news coverage particular to the Jewish community, while later issues expand the scope of coverage. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- The Link, 1983-1993; 1 Reels
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Brownsville and East New York, The Link provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, and culture. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Serving as the organ for its publisher, the United Community Centers Inc., The Link covers stories of particular social, political, and civic interest. Numerous articles about garbage dumps and incinerators in and around East New York appear regularly as do articles concerning education issues facing young children. A page entitled "This Month in Labor History" regularly appears as does coverage of local political activism. Recipes from community members are also regularly published. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Midwood Sentry, 1983-1984; Partial reel (same reel as North Brooklyn News). (Bin 30)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Midwood, the Midwood Sentry provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, religion, sports, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Regularly appearing columns include: "Eye on the Arts" highlighting community artists; and "Midwood People" which profiles local residents. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout
- Mill Basin Civic News, 1940-1985; 2 Reels (Bin 28)